A Guide to the Virginia Home Economics Association: Committee for the Standardization of Consumer Goods Records, 1930-1936
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Virginia A Guide to the Virginia Home Economics Association: Committee for the Stadardization of Consumer Goods 1930-1936
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms63-001
1 Folder, 0.1 cu. ft.
Collection contains correspondence and reports of the Committee for the Standardization of Consumer Goods.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated in 1963
Biographical Information
In the early twentieth-century, seven women including Mary Ledger Moffett founded the Virginia Home Economics Association. This organization's Committee for the Standardization of Consumer Goods, chaired during the 1930s by Ilena M. Bailey, focused on the creation of quality standards for products such as blankets, sheets, pillowcases, stockings, canned food, and refrigerators.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of correspondence and reports from 1930 to 1936 of Ilena M. Bailey, home economics researcher at Virginia Tech and chairperson of the Committee for the Standardization of Consumer Goods. Materials include correspondence with department store managers, government agencies and women's organizations.
Contents List
- Virginia Home Economics Association: Committee for the Standardization of Consumer Goods 1930-1936 (Folder 1)
  - Virginia Manufacturers n.d.
  - Harry F. Byrd May 21, 1934
  - Marry Brown Allgood April 11, 1935
  - G. L. Webster Canning Company April 9, 1935
  - National Better Business Bureau March 4, 1936
  - Virginia Home Economics Association April 2, 1934; April 11, 1935
  - Report of the Committee on the Standardization of Consumer Goods 1932-33
  - Chatham Manufacturing Company April 6, 9, 1936
  - Jean J. Stewart, College of William and Mary October 3, 15, 1934
  - Virginia Federation of Women's Clubs March 16, 19, 1932; April 2, 4, 30, 1934
  - American Association of University Women in Virginia April 2, 1934
  - Consumers National Conference Newletter January 15, 1934
  - American Standards Association February 23, April 27, 1932
  - Virginia State Board of Education April 11; March 15, 19, 1932, March 19, 20, 1934
  - General Federation of Women's Clubs February 23, 1932
  - National Association of Ice Industries March 3, 1930
  - Sears, Roebuck, and Company October 19, 1933
  - S. H. Heironimus Company March 16, 19, 1932
  - Miller and Rhoads Inc. March 16, 19, 1932
  - Smith and Welton Inc. March 21, 1932
  - Thalhimer Brothers March 22, 1932
  - United States Bureau of Home Economics May 8, 31; June 12, 20, 1935
  - American Home Economics Association February 23; March 8, 17;April 1; June 21, August 2, 8, 1932
  - American Home Economics Association February 23; March 8, 17;April 1; June 21, August 2, 8, 1932